<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Marc.ai</title>
    <link href="https://marc.ai/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://marc.ai" />
    <updated>2024-07-06T18:51:57-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Marc Stogaitis</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://marc.ai</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Probabilistic Chess</title>
        <author>
            <name>Marc Stogaitis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://marc.ai/probabilistic-chess.html"/>
        <id>https://marc.ai/probabilistic-chess.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://marc.ai/media/posts/10/android-chrome-192x192.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-07-06T18:51:57-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/10/android-chrome-192x192.png" alt="Probabilistic Chess" />
                    Introducing Probabilistic Chess An exciting new variant of chess that you can play at marc.ai/probchess. For example, if you attempt to move a pawn from e2 to e4 and e4 has a 60% success probability, you will see a dice roll animation. The dice will&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/10/android-chrome-192x192.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Probabilistic Chess" /></p>
                <h3>Introducing Probabilistic Chess</h3>
<p>An exciting new variant of chess that you can play at <a rel="noreferrer" target="_new" href="https://marc.ai/probchess"></a><a href="https://marc.ai/probchess" target="_new">marc.ai/probchess</a>.</p>
<h3>The Rules:</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Movement Probability</strong>: Each square on the board has a probability of successfully moving to it.</li>
<li><strong>Dice Roll</strong>: A happy-face dice roll means the move was successful.</li>
<li><strong>Winning Condition</strong>: You win by capturing the opponent's king.</li>
</ul>
<p>For example, if you attempt to move a pawn from e2 to e4 and e4 has a 60% success probability, you will see a dice roll animation. The dice will have a 60% chance of landing on a happy face and a 40% chance of landing on a sad face. If it lands on a happy face, the move succeeds. If it lands on a sad face, the move fails, the pawn returns to e2, and it's now the opponent’s turn.</p>
<p><video loading="lazy" width="688" height="531" autoplay="autoplay" muted="" loop="loop">
        <source src="https://marc.ai/assets/video/probabilistic-chess-video.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
        Your browser does not support the video tag.
    </video></p>
<h3>Capturing the King</h3>
<p>An intriguing aspect of probabilistic chess is that <strong>checkmate no longer guarantees a win</strong>. In traditional chess, checkmate ends the game because it ensures the king will be captured. However, in probabilistic chess, capturing the king is not guaranteed. The king may be on a low probability square, making it challenging to capture. Additionally, the opponent may capture your king while you attempt to capture theirs, or the king might escape while you try to capture it. Therefore, thinking probabilistically and strategizing based on square probabilities is crucial.</p>
<p>Key points:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Checkmate</strong>: Checkmate does not win the game; capturing the king does.</li>
<li><strong>Moves During Check</strong>: You can make moves while your king is in check.</li>
<li><strong>Self-Check</strong>: You can make moves that put your king in check.</li>
</ul>
<p>This dynamic adds a fun twist to chess. Traditional chess often ends with a checkmate without ever capturing the king, but now, you get the satisfaction of an actual capture (or the frustration of a failed attempt).</p>
<h3>All Games End in a Win</h3>
<p>Due to the probabilistic nature of the board, traditional draw scenarios do not apply. Stalemates are impossible because the king can always attempt to escape, and the opponent might fail to capture it. Even with only two kings left, they can capture each other by moving to low probability squares. If one king tries to capture and fails, the other can succeed.</p>
<p>This rule change is similar to modifications in professional sports to eliminate draws, like hockey's overtime and shootouts or the NBA's continual overtimes until a winner is declared.</p>
<p>Always having a game end in a win is enjoyable. However, it may need adjustment if players can prolong the game indefinitely, such as with two kings avoiding each other. A potential solution could be a "shrinking board" algorithm where the board gradually gets smaller, forcing the kings toward each other.</p>
<p>Feedback on handling these scenarios or reintroducing draws is welcome.</p>
<h3>Variants</h3>
<p>While I like the simplicity of the default rules, we're testing out different variants of the game based on our experience playing it. You can try these out in the 'Variants' drop-down section of the site.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>King Moves Always Succeed</strong>: King moves are always successful.</li>
<li><strong>King Moves Double Success Rate</strong>: King moves have double the success rate of the destination square.</li>
</ul>
<p>These 'king move' variants were introduced to reduce the chances of winning simply by constantly attacking the king and getting a lucky dice roll as it can be frustrating to lose when far ahead simply because the opponent YOLO's their pieces at your king. There may be a way to play to lower the odds of this, or maybe these variants are needed. We'd love some feedback on if a variant should become part of the core game mechanics.</p>
<h3>Implementation Details</h3>
<h4>Board Probabilities Setup</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Random Initialization</strong>: Probabilities are randomly set at the start of each game.</li>
<li><strong>King Square</strong>: Starts with a probability of at least 10%. This lowers the chances of having the king start on an almost uncapturable square.</li>
<li><strong>Minimum Probability</strong>: 2% for any square.</li>
<li><strong>Maximum Probability</strong>: 99% for any square.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Note: These rules may change as the game evolves.</em></p>
<h4>Client-Side Implementation</h4>
<p>The game is implemented purely in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to run without a server. This approach ensures fast loading times and low server costs but poses challenges for creating a performant chess AI.</p>
<h3>Chess AI</h3>
<p>Creating a chess AI for Probabilistic Chess is a fun project. The AI combines chess.js and stockfish.js.</p>
<h4>Stockfish AI (Moderate)</h4>
<p>This AI uses Stockfish to determine the best move. While Stockfish is a strong chess program, it does not account for probabilities, resulting in occasional poor decisions, like repeatedly attempting moves to low probability squares.</p>
<h4>Alpha-Beta with Expectation-Maximization (Hard and Expert)</h4>
<p>This is the primary AI for the game, incorporating an alpha-beta search algorithm and the expectation-maximization algorithm to consider board probabilities. It calculates:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Move Success Score: </strong>The score if the move succeeds, by recursively calling alpha-beta and calling stockfish's eval method once the desired depth is reached.</li>
<li><strong>Move Failed Score</strong>: The score if the move fails and it’s the opponent’s turn.</li>
<li><strong>Expected Value</strong>: <code>moveSuccessScore * probOfMoveSucceeding + moveFailedScore * (1 - probOfMoveSucceeding)</code></li>
</ul>
<p>This runs recursively up to a certain depth, using the traditional chess alpha-beta search algorithm. When it reaches the desired depth, it asks Stockfish to provide an eval for the position.</p>
<p>This seems to work pretty well and results in a decently strong opponent that takes square probabilities into account.</p>
<p>Additional details:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Performance</strong>: Running a large search tree in JavaScript is slow, limiting the search depth.</li>
<li><strong>Multi-threading</strong>: I'm considering a newer, multi-threaded version of Stockfish's JavaScript engine, though it requires setting CORS headers which my host doesn't support. I'm going to try one of the documented workarounds.</li>
<li><strong>AI vs. AI</strong>: You can set AIs for both black and white to watch them play against each other.</li>
<li><strong>Endgame Issues</strong>: There can be problems when the AI believes the game is over (e.g. it’s way ahead, or the game is a draw). At this point, most moves have an identical score so it doesn’t quite know what to do. I’m looking at improving this.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Monte Carlo Simulation</h4>
<p>This earlier algorithm ran several simulations using Stockfish's top moves to determine the best move based on average scores. It worked decently but was slow and is no longer actively developed.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>Developing Probabilistic Chess has been a lot of fun. My dad and I have spent over 30 years working on programming projects together and a big part of that was focused on ML and applying it to chess so building a new variant of chess together has been great.</p>
<h3>Credits</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Created by</strong>: Marc Stogaitis and Guy Stogaitis</li>
<li><strong>Special Thanks</strong>: Ghislaine Stogaitis and Mimi Sun</li>
<li><strong>Inspired by</strong>: Cameron Sun’s probabilistic tic-tac-toe</li>
<li><strong>Libraries Used</strong>: chess.js, stockfish.js</li>
<li><strong>Try out <a href="https://marc.ai/probchess">probabilistic chess here</a>.</strong></li>
</ul>
<h3>Contact</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Twitter</strong>: <a href="https://x.com/marcsto" title="Marc Stogaitis on X.com (Twitter)" target="_new">@marcsto</a></li>
<li><strong>Email</strong>: marcsto@gmail.com</li>
</ul>
<p>Please <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Check%20out%20Probabilistic%20Chess!%20@marcsto&amp;url=https://marc.ai/probchess">share Probabilistic Chess</a> with your friends!</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/10/probabilistic-chess-screenshot.PNG" alt="Probabilistic Chess Screenshot" width="900" height="730" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://marc.ai/media/posts/10/responsive/probabilistic-chess-screenshot-xs.PNG 300w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/10/responsive/probabilistic-chess-screenshot-sm.PNG 480w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/10/responsive/probabilistic-chess-screenshot-md.PNG 768w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/10/responsive/probabilistic-chess-screenshot-lg.PNG 1024w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/10/responsive/probabilistic-chess-screenshot-xl.PNG 1360w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/10/responsive/probabilistic-chess-screenshot-2xl.PNG 1600w"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Full Research Papers on Youtube</title>
        <author>
            <name>Marc Stogaitis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://marc.ai/full-research-papers-on-youtube.html"/>
        <id>https://marc.ai/full-research-papers-on-youtube.html</id>

        <updated>2020-05-25T19:22:02-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Reading research papers takes a lot of time. On top of that, I personally prefer to consume content through audio + video rather than through reading alone. To make it easier to read more papers, I'm doing an experiment where I make&nbsp;videos that show the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    Reading research papers takes a lot of time. On top of that, I personally prefer to consume content through audio + video rather than through reading alone.
  </p>

  <p>
    To make it easier to read more papers, I'm doing an experiment where I make<b>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqTc8u62Cf-V5qNM6mk7J1A">videos</a> that show the full text of a research paper, images as well as reads the paper out loud</b>.&nbsp;
  </p>
<div><b>You might enjoy this if you:</b>
<ul>
<li>Prefer to learn through hearing rather than reading alone.</li>
<li>Like to take a first-pass through a paper while commuting.</li>
<li>Spend long days staring at a screen and want to give your eyes a rest, lay back and hear a research paper at the end of the day.</li>
<li>Have a backlog of research papers to read and would like to catch up by reading some of them more casually.</li>
<li>Want to take a first-pass through a paper before deciding if it’s worth sitting down and working through the details.</li>
</ul></div>

  <p>
    <b>How it works:</b><b><br></b>The videos are a combination of manual video editing and automated generation to make it easier to create. The key is using a cloud-based text to speech engine for reading out the full text. I find most text to speech voices pretty annoying but after some experimentation, I've found that using Google's WaveNet non-real-time cloud-based text to speech&nbsp;has the best sounding voice. <b>I was pleasantly surprised to find a voice I enjoy hearing</b>. (<i>Full disclosure: I work at Google, but I have nothing to do with their text to speech offering nor Google cloud. This is just my personal opinion after testing out several different text to speech engines</i>).<br>
  </p>

    <h2 id="videos">
      Videos
    </h2>

  <p>
    You can find all videos at this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqTc8u62Cf-V5qNM6mk7J1A">YouTube channel</a>. Here's a sample of what's on there:
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l8BtqFxo8gw">PersonLab: Pose Estimation &amp; Instance Segmentation with a Bottom-Up Geometric Embedding</a>&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MvsUpktOmkI">The Lottery Ticket Hypothesis: Finding Sparse, Trainable Neural Networks</a>
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=saSLTjQKuN0">Accelerating Self-Play Learning in Go</a>
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7C3abmLlUVw" target="_blank">Mastering Atari, Go, Chess and Shogi by Planning with a Learned Model</a>
  </p>

  <p>
    I tend to post papers I’m interested in, but if you have a paper you’d like me to generate a video for just send me a message on twitter at https://twitter.com/marcsto or email me at marcsto@gmail.com and I should be able to help
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Punch Corona Frequently Asked Questions</title>
        <author>
            <name>Marc Stogaitis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://marc.ai/punch-corona-frequently-asked-questions.html"/>
        <id>https://marc.ai/punch-corona-frequently-asked-questions.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/Screenshot-from-2020-05-06-16-36-53.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2020-05-09T12:46:41-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/Screenshot-from-2020-05-06-16-36-53.png" alt="" />
                    What is Punch Corona? Punch Corona is a workout game where you get to beat up the corona virus. It uses machine learning to track your movements using your computer's camera. Where can I find it? It's available at&nbsp;https://marc.ai/punch-corona/ What’s the difference between green and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/Screenshot-from-2020-05-06-16-36-53.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                
  <p>
    <b>What is Punch Corona?</b> <a href="https://marc.ai/punch-corona/">Punch Corona</a> is a workout game where you get to beat up the corona virus. It uses machine learning to track your movements using your computer's camera.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>Where can I find it?</b> It's available at&nbsp;<a href="https://marc.ai/punch-corona/">https://marc.ai/punch-corona/</a>
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>What’s the difference between green and red viruses?&nbsp;</b>Green should targets should be hit with the right hand, red with the left hand
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>What are the green and red semi-transparent cubes?</b> These represent the location of your hands. As you move your hands in the real-world, the boxes should move with you. Your goal is to punch the viruses by moving the boxes.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>Do the camera images get uploaded to a server?</b> No. All processing happens locally on your computer to preserve your privacy.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>It doesn’t track my hands properly. What should I do?</b>
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li>The most common issue is standing too close to your webcam. Try taking 2 long strides away from your computer (you should be standing about <b>1.5 meters, or 5 feet from your webcam</b>).</li><li>Make sure that your hands aren't leaving view of the camera when extending upwards or to the side. You can either move backwards more to fix this or punch less far.</li>
  </ul>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/onboarding-logo.png" height="1292" width="1292" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/onboarding-logo-xs.png 300w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/onboarding-logo-sm.png 480w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/onboarding-logo-md.png 768w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/onboarding-logo-lg.png 1024w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/onboarding-logo-xl.png 1360w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/onboarding-logo-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    <b>How can I test my setup?</b>&nbsp;Join a game but ignore punching things for now. Try moving your hands up, down, left and right and see how well the red and green semi-transparent cubes are tracking. Also, take a look at the top right of the screen. You'll see what your camera sees as well as lines representing where it thinks your arms, eyes, and torso are. <b>Make sure that the line to your wrist is always in-frame.</b> You can do additional testing <a href="https://storage.googleapis.com/tfjs-models/demos/posenet/camera.html" target="_blank">here</a>.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>The game runs slowly:</b>&nbsp;Try hitting the "Improve Performance" button at the bottom of the screen.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>There’s a lot of lag between when I move my hand and when it shows up on screen:</b>&nbsp;Sorry about that. This alpha release needs a fairly powerful CPU to run the game as it needs to run both the game and a machine learning model that tracks your body movements. It's something we're working to improve. Try hitting the "Improve Performance" button to see if that helps. If it doesn't, contact me at marcsto@gmail.com with a bit of info on your computer specs and I'll see what I can do.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>How do I switch to a different webcam?</b>
  </p>

  <ol>
    <li>In chrome, go into Settings.</li><li>Search for camera<br></li><li>Click 'Site Settings'</li><li>Click 'Camera'</li><li>At the top, change which camera is selected in the drop-down menu.</li><li>Reload the game</li>
  </ol>

  <p>
    <b>Do I really need to punch the viruses, or can I just put my hands in front of them?</b> Technically for now, you just need to move your hands in front of the . But that's not as satisfying as punching the corona virus and making is blow-up now is it? It's also a much better workout if you punch the viruses.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>Who created the Punch Corona game?</b>&nbsp;It was developed by Marc Stogaitis with the help of Mimi Sun.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>Acknowledgements</b>
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li>Created by Marc Stogaitis and Mimi Sun</li><li>We'd like to thank Dan Oved, Google Creative Lab and TensorFlow.js for their contributions to open source libraries that we used in this project.<br></li><li>Assets for the on-boarding flow are from&nbsp;https://www.freepik.com</li><li>The song is called <a href="https://www.bensound.com/royalty-free-music/track/happy-rock" target="_blank">happyrock</a> and is available on bensound.</li>
  </ul>

  <p>
    <b>Where can I learn more? </b>There's more info in the&nbsp;<a href="https://marc.ai/introducing-punch-corona-alpha-release.html">initial blog post here</a>. You can also contact marcsto@gmail.com with any questions.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/Screenshot-from-2020-05-06-16-36-53.png" height="1282" width="2538" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/Screenshot-from-2020-05-06-16-36-53-xs.png 300w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/Screenshot-from-2020-05-06-16-36-53-sm.png 480w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/Screenshot-from-2020-05-06-16-36-53-md.png 768w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/Screenshot-from-2020-05-06-16-36-53-lg.png 1024w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/Screenshot-from-2020-05-06-16-36-53-xl.png 1360w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/7/responsive/Screenshot-from-2020-05-06-16-36-53-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Introducing Punch Corona (Alpha Release)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Marc Stogaitis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://marc.ai/introducing-punch-corona-alpha-release.html"/>
        <id>https://marc.ai/introducing-punch-corona-alpha-release.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://marc.ai/media/posts/1/punch-corona-1.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2020-05-06T17:36:34-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/1/punch-corona-1.png" alt="" />
                    Punch Corona is a workout game where you get to beat up the corona virus. It uses machine learning to track your movements using your computer's camera. No data ever leaves your device to preserve your privacy. It's a great way to spend your quarantine&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/1/punch-corona-1.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                
  <p>
    <br><b><a href="https://marc.ai/punch-corona/" target="_blank">Punch Corona</a></b> is a workout game where you get to beat up the corona virus. It uses machine learning to track your movements using your computer's camera. No data ever leaves your device to preserve your privacy.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>It's a great way to spend your quarantine time or get back in shape after gaining the quarantine 15</b>.
  </p>

  <p>
    It detects your body movements from a simple webcam which means you don't need any special hardware like a Kinect or VR controller for a completely hands-free experience.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/1/punch-corona-1.png" height="1286" width="2540" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://marc.ai/media/posts/1/responsive/punch-corona-1-xs.png 300w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/1/responsive/punch-corona-1-sm.png 480w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/1/responsive/punch-corona-1-md.png 768w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/1/responsive/punch-corona-1-lg.png 1024w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/1/responsive/punch-corona-1-xl.png 1360w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/1/responsive/punch-corona-1-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    One pro tip: the most common issue is standing too close to the camera. <b>Make sure to stand far enough back so that your camera can see your entire upper body</b> and can still see your hands when they are stretched out punching up or down.
  </p>

  <p>
    This is an alpha release, so you may encounter issues. It needs a pretty good machine to run smoothly as it has to run both the game and a machine learning model to track your body movements. Email me at marcsto@gmail.com to let me know if you encounter any problems or if you enjoy the game.
  </p>

  <p>
    Check it out at <a href="https://marc.ai/punch-corona/">https://marc.ai/punch-corona/</a>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Don&#x27;t Touch Your Face</title>
        <author>
            <name>Marc Stogaitis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://marc.ai/dont-touch-face.html"/>
        <id>https://marc.ai/dont-touch-face.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://marc.ai/media/posts/2/appicon.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2020-05-06T19:51:56-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/2/appicon.png" alt="" />
                    Don’t touch your face. This is a key recommendation from health organizations to help prevent the spread of the novel coronavirus COVID-19. But avoiding touching your face is hard! DontTouchFace.com is here to help. It combines the front-facing camera on your computer or phone with&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/2/appicon.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                
  <p>
    <b>Don’t touch your face</b>. This is a key recommendation from health organizations to help prevent the spread of the novel coronavirus COVID-19. But avoiding touching your face is hard!
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/2/dont-touch-face.png" height="480" width="641" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://marc.ai/media/posts/2/responsive/dont-touch-face-xs.png 300w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/2/responsive/dont-touch-face-sm.png 480w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/2/responsive/dont-touch-face-md.png 768w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/2/responsive/dont-touch-face-lg.png 1024w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/2/responsive/dont-touch-face-xl.png 1360w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/2/responsive/dont-touch-face-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    <b><a href="https://donttouchface.com" target="_blank">DontTouchFace.com</a></b> is here to help. It combines the front-facing camera on your computer or phone with advanced machine learning techniques to warn you when you touch your face. This helps you become aware of when you touch your face and reduce how often it happens over time.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>So how does it work?</b> It uses computer vision to detect the location of your face and hand and warns you if they intersect. You'll hear a 'beep' making you aware that you're touching your face. Just remember to <b>turn on your speakers or put on your headphones</b>.
  </p>

  <p>
    No camera data ever leaves your device which is great to preserve your privacy.
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://DontTouchFace.com" class="" target="_blank">DontTouchFace.com</a> was created by Marc Stogaitis and Mimi Sun.&nbsp;We'd like to thank Ann Yuan, Andrey Vakunov, MediaPipe, TensorFlow.js and Google Research for their contributions to open source libraries that we used in this project.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="" height="512" width="512" alt=""  data-is-external-image="true">
      
    </figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Celebrity Look-alike for Android</title>
        <author>
            <name>Marc Stogaitis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://marc.ai/celebrity-look-alike-for-android.html"/>
        <id>https://marc.ai/celebrity-look-alike-for-android.html</id>

        <updated>2020-05-06T21:23:28-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Celebrity Look-alike is a fun little Android app that determines which celebrities look like you. It uses machine learning based on a deep neural network to search through a database of over 20 000 celebrities. It's remarkably accurate! You can enter a picture by: The&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ai.marc.lookalike" target="_blank">Celebrity Look-alike</a> is a fun little Android app that determines which celebrities look like you.<br><br>It uses machine learning based on a deep neural network to search through a database of over 20 000 celebrities. It's remarkably accurate!
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/3/celebrity-look-alike.png" height="1279" width="1448" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://marc.ai/media/posts/3/responsive/celebrity-look-alike-xs.png 300w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/3/responsive/celebrity-look-alike-sm.png 480w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/3/responsive/celebrity-look-alike-md.png 768w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/3/responsive/celebrity-look-alike-lg.png 1024w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/3/responsive/celebrity-look-alike-xl.png 1360w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/3/responsive/celebrity-look-alike-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    You can enter a picture by:
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li><span style="color: var(--eb-text-primary-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: 1em; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Taking a picture</span><br></li><li>Selecting an existing photo from your gallery or Google Photos</li>
  </ul>

  <p>
    The app shows you your top celebrity matches. It may also include what you would look like as an older, younger, larger, smaller, female and male celebrity.<br><br>A nice privacy feature of using the Android Celebrity Look-alike app is that all the processing happens directly on your device so your photos are never sent to a server which respects your privacy.
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Doodlecast for Chromecast Android App</title>
        <author>
            <name>Marc Stogaitis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://marc.ai/doodlecast-for-chromecast-android-app.html"/>
        <id>https://marc.ai/doodlecast-for-chromecast-android-app.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/doodlecast-bird.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2020-05-06T21:22:51-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/doodlecast-bird.png" alt="" />
                    Doodlecast for Chromecast is a fun drawing game that pairs your Android phone and Chromecast together so you can play as a group. One player picks a secret word to draw on their phone or tablet while the other players in the room try to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/doodlecast-bird.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                
  <p>
    <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.mimisun.doodlecast" target="_blank">Doodlecast for Chromecast</a> is a fun drawing game that pairs your Android phone and Chromecast together so you can play as a group.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/doodlecast-bird.png" height="1005" width="1911" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-bird-xs.png 300w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-bird-sm.png 480w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-bird-md.png 768w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-bird-lg.png 1024w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-bird-xl.png 1360w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-bird-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    One player picks a secret word to draw on their phone or tablet while the other players in the room try to guess it. The drawing and guesses are simultaneously displayed on the TV. It’s a fun game to play with your friends and family!
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>Features</b>:<br>
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li>Draw on your phone, see it appear on your TV using your Chromecast!</li><li>Choose from a large list of words to draw</li><li>Other players in the room see what is being drawn on the Chromecast enabled TV and use their phones to guess the word</li><li>Players rotate turns, so everyone has a chance to draw!</li><li>Works even if you only have 1 Android phone</li><li>Works with both phones and tablets</li>
  </ul>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/doodlecast-logo.png" height="138" width="180" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-logo-xs.png 300w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-logo-sm.png 480w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-logo-md.png 768w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-logo-lg.png 1024w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-logo-xl.png 1360w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/4/responsive/doodlecast-logo-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>PicLearn Helps You Learn Chinese and French</title>
        <author>
            <name>Marc Stogaitis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://marc.ai/piclearn-helps-you-learn-chinese-and-french.html"/>
        <id>https://marc.ai/piclearn-helps-you-learn-chinese-and-french.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/piclearn-audio-recognition.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2020-05-06T21:22:19-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/piclearn-audio-recognition.png" alt="" />
                    PicLearn are 2 Android apps that help you learn either&nbsp;Mandarin Chinese or French in a fun and visual way. Learn new words with pictures and sounds, and perfect your pronunciation through the use of voice recognition. With PicLearn, you can learn and review words on&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/piclearn-audio-recognition.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                
  <p>
    PicLearn are 2 Android apps that help you learn either&nbsp;<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.piclearn.client.chinese.free" target="_blank">Mandarin Chinese</a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.piclearn.client.french" target="_blank">French</a> in a fun and visual way. Learn new words with pictures and sounds, and perfect your pronunciation through the use of voice recognition.<br>
  </p>

  <div  class="gallery-wrapper">
    <div class="gallery" data-columns="3">
      <figure class="gallery__item">
      <a href="https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/gallery/piclearn-front.png" data-size="400x693">
        <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/gallery/piclearn-front-thumbnail.png" height="693" width="400" alt="" >
      </a>
      
    </figure><figure class="gallery__item">
      <a href="https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/gallery/piclearn-images.png" data-size="400x703">
        <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/gallery/piclearn-images-thumbnail.png" height="703" width="400" alt="" >
      </a>
      
    </figure>
    </div>
  </div>

  <p>
    With PicLearn, you can learn and review words on the go and build up your Chinese vocabulary.&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    You can select between 3 modes:
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li><b>PicIt</b> presents you with a Mandarin Chinese word and 4 images. Tap the image that represents the word.</li><li><b>SayIt</b> uses voice recognition to help you practice your prononciation. Tap the microphone picture and say the word that the image represents.</li><li><b>CueIt</b> shows you cue cards which you can use to quickly learn a new set of words.</li>
  </ul>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/piclearn-logo2.png" height="149" width="302" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/responsive/piclearn-logo2-xs.png 300w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/responsive/piclearn-logo2-sm.png 480w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/responsive/piclearn-logo2-md.png 768w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/responsive/piclearn-logo2-lg.png 1024w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/responsive/piclearn-logo2-xl.png 1360w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/5/responsive/piclearn-logo2-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About Marc Stogaitis</title>
        <author>
            <name>Marc Stogaitis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://marc.ai/about-marc-stogaitis.html"/>
        <id>https://marc.ai/about-marc-stogaitis.html</id>

        <updated>2020-05-09T13:39:53-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I like to work on personal projects on weekends for fun and to learn new things. That's what this site is about.&nbsp; Machine Learning Android Apps Work I'm a Principal Software Engineer at Google.&nbsp;I'm on the Android team and work on the following projects: Talks&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    I like to work on personal projects on weekends for fun and to learn new things. That's what this site is about.&nbsp;
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://marc.ai/media/posts/6/marc-with-android.jpg" height="1067" width="1600" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://marc.ai/media/posts/6/responsive/marc-with-android-xs.jpg 300w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/6/responsive/marc-with-android-sm.jpg 480w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/6/responsive/marc-with-android-md.jpg 768w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/6/responsive/marc-with-android-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/6/responsive/marc-with-android-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://marc.ai/media/posts/6/responsive/marc-with-android-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    <b>Machine Learning</b>
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li>My dad and I have spent the last 22 years learning about machine learning by applying it to different games, focusing on chess. It started out as vb6 &amp; c++. These days, it focuses Java and TensorFlow in python. For example, I've been implementing a version of Alpha Zero for chess.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/marcsto/rl">Github link</a> with some small experiments applying reinforcement learning to OpenAi Gym (sorry, most of my code is in a private repository but I do try to post interesting bits in the public github from time to time).</li>
  </ul>

  <p>
    <b>Android Apps</b>
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li><a href="https://marc.ai/punch-corona/index.html" target="_blank">Punch Corona (Alpha)</a>: A workout game where you get to beat up the corona virus. It uses machine learning to track your movements using your computer's camera. No data ever leaves your device to preserve your privacy.</li><li><a href="https://DontTouchFace.com" target="_blank">DontTouchFace.com</a>:&nbsp;Combines the front-facing camera on your computer or phone with machine learning to warn you when you touch your face.</li><li><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ai.marc.lookalike" target="_blank" class="">Celebrity Look-alike</a>: Find out which celebrities look like you.</li><li><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.mimisun.doodlecast" target="_blank">Doodlecast for Chromecast</a>: A fun drawing game for your Chromecast that you can play as a group.</li><li><a href="http://www.gmote.org" target="_blank" class="">Gmote</a>: Turns your phone into a remote control for your computer, allowing you to start and control movies and music at a distance.</li><li><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.piclearn.client.french" target="_blank">PicLearn French</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.piclearn.client.chinese.free" target="_blank">PicLearn Chinese</a>:  Helps you learn french and Mandarin Chinese in a fun and visual way. Learn new words with pictures and sounds. Perfect your pronunciation through the use of voice recognition.<br></li>
  </ul>
<hr class="separator separator--dots" />

  <p>
    <b>Work</b>
  </p>

  <p>
    I'm a Principal Software Engineer at Google.&nbsp;I'm on the Android team and work on the following projects:
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li><a href="https://developers.google.com/location-context/fused-location-provider/">Fused Location</a></li><li><a href="https://developers.google.com/location-context/activity-recognition/">Activity Recognition</a></li><li><a href="https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/sensors/sensors_overview.html">Android Sensors</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2015/09/29/the-new-android-sensor-hub-will-significantly-improve-idle-battery-life-while-doing-more-with-sensor-data/">Android Sensor Hub</a></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/1/20892875/google-pixel-personal-safety-app-car-crash-detection">Car Crash Detection</a></li>
  </ul>

  <p>
    <b>Talks</b>
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5MIBNOTD_mM">Google I/O Android Sensors &amp; Location: What's New &amp; Best Practices</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S8sugXgUVEI">Activity Recognition: Use low power sensors to detect user activity (100 Days of Google Dev)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xgcj7VbDalk">Google I/O: Making apps context aware</a></li>
  </ul>

  <p>
    You can reach me at marcsto@gmail.com
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
